您这次要参加的是什么样的巡航
So what kind of cruise is this you're going on?
这次水上之行称为"重生之旅"
It's called the Born Again Boat Ride.
基督教季刊给予了这次旅途最高的评价
Christian Quarterly gave it their highest rating--
五颗荆棘王冠呢
five thorny crowns.
我真希望你能跟我一起去  谢尔顿
I do wish you'd come with me, Sheldon.
老妈  如果我去了就等于直接证明
Well, Mom, if I did, it would be conclusive proof
您的神真的能造就奇迹
that your God can work miracles.
这你可就错了
You're missing out.
到时候欢乐肯定无所不在
It's gonna be wall-to-wall fun.
全都有主题哦
It's all themed.
届时能看到"约拿和鲸鱼"[圣经故事]
There's Jonah and the Whale watching.
你还能吃到名为"最后的晚餐"的自助餐
All-you-can-eat Last Supper Buffet.
以及我本人的最爱  "神之恕击"
And my personal favorite, Gunning with God.
我冒昧的问一下  什么叫"神之恕击"
What's Gunning with God? I'm afraid to ask.
说起来非常的有趣
Oh, it is a hoot and a half.
首先将你的罪恶写在一个泥制飞靶上
You write your sins on a clay pigeon,
再用机器把靶子弹射出去
they fire 'em up in the air,
然后你拿一把12发弹容的散弹枪打爆它
and you pulverize them with a 12-gauge shotgun
充满了神的宽恕啊
full of our Lord's forgiveness.
老实说  妈妈  我很高兴看到
Frankly, Mom, I'm encouraged to see
你们天主教团思想进步了
how advanced your group has become--
敢于出海
you are willing to sail out into the ocean
不再担心地球是平的 船会摔下去
without fear of falling off the edge.
暗讽《圣经》里多处暗示大地是一块平板
打个比方
For example,
如果谢利在船上  他应该
if Shelly was aboard, he'd write,
在飞靶写上"牙尖嘴利"
"Smart mouth" on his pigeon,
然后来个五雷轰顶
and then bam!
神予之 神毁之
The Lord giveth and the Lord bloweth away.
老妈  根据我们以往周末的安排
Well, Mom, according to my itinerary for our weekend together,
-欢乐应该始于炸鸡  -听起来很美味啊
- the fun begins with fried chicken. - Sounds delicious.
很好  因为我已经帮你备齐了所有材料
Good, 'cause I got you everything you need to make it.
你有口福了
You are in for a treat.
我爸的棺材
My mother's fried chicken
之所以变成加大号的  就是因为我妈的炸鸡美味
is why we had to buy my dad the extra large coffin.
谢尔顿  她刚下飞机
Sheldon, she just got off the plane.
她不想做饭了
She doesn't want to cook.
她当然想做
Of course she does.
做饭给我吃  是她向我表达"我爱你"的方式
Making me food is her way of saying "I love you""
在她筋疲力尽的时候做给我吃
Making me food when she's too tired to cook
是她向我表达"我真的很爱你"的方式
is her way of saying "I really love you."
其实我并不介意出去吃  谢尔顿
Actually, I wouldn't mind going out for a bite, Sheldon.
吃那些粗粮
Won't that spoil our appetites
会坏了吃炸鸡的好胃口吧
for the chicken you're going to make me?
好了  就这么定了  我们出去吃
All right, that settles it, we're going out.
你喜欢吃寿司吗  街上有家小店不错
Do you like sushi? There's a great little place down the street.
我没吃过寿司
I've never had it,
不过试试新鲜事物总没什么坏处
but there's no harm in trying something new.
尝试新鲜事物坏处多了
There's a lot of harm in trying something new.
所以要用兔子来测试药物和化妆品的安全性
That's why we test out drugs and cosmetics on bunny rabbits.
谢尔顿  你的言行像个疯子
Sheldon, you're talking like a crazy person.
其实  他小时候我带他检查过了
Actually, I had him tested as a child.
医生说他很正常
Doctor says he's fine.
早跟你说了
Told you.
虽然我很后悔没接着去找
Although, I do regret not following up
休斯顿的那位专家
with that specialist in Houston.
■
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 翻译制作
更多美剧原创翻译 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：米小勒  海因里希  Tina  小蛮腰
后期：鱼骨头    时间轴：YY
■
校对：Joanna  YY      总监：YY
生活大爆炸  第五季第六集
欢迎光临
いらっしゃいます
别瞎嚷嚷了
Stop yelling!
来这儿我很不开心
I'm not happy about this.
你这辈子什么时候开心过吗
What's the last thing you were ever happy about?
等着吃炸鸡的时候
The prospect of fried chicken.
真令人激动
This is exciting.
咱家四号公路线那的馆子也卖寿司
Back home, the diner on Route Four serves sushi,
但他们只是把炸鱼排切碎
but it's just cut up fish sticks
再配上"本恩大叔"牌速食米饭
and a side of Uncle Ben's.
即使他们用"功夫文"写菜单
They put it on the menu in those kung fu letters,
但假货就假货
but that don't make it sushi.
额  "功夫文"好像有点种族歧视吧
Uh, kung fu letters might not be politically correct.
ching chong:外国人模仿中国话发音  变相对亚洲人的种族诋毁的词语
我还以为只有"ching chong"是不能说的呢
Oh, I thought the one we couldn't say was "ching chong"
额  对  那个也不能说
Yeah, yeah, that, too.
谢利
So, Shelly,
你和你的朋友艾米进展如何了
what's up with you and your friend Amy,
如果你不介意妈妈窥探点隐私的话
if you don't mind a mother prying a bit?
艾米的确有大进展
Well, there's actually big news on the Amy front.
她最近在研究
She's been studying
神经生物学中有关低等生物的上瘾问题
the neurobiology of addiction in lower animals.
她就差这么一点点  就能让海星迷上可卡因了
She's this close to getting a starfish hooked on cocaine.
你知道他们两个发展的情况吗
Do you have any idea what's going on with those two?
他们俩的关系就像尼斯湖水怪
It's kind of like the Loch Ness monster.
也许事实存在  也许不存在
Maybe there's something there, maybe there isn't.
真相可能永远藏在湖里
We'll probably never know.
偷想这问题来惊吓一下自己  还是挺有意思的
But sometimes it's fun to creep yourself out thinking about it.
你跟年轻女孩子相处得怎样
How are you doing on the young lady front?
我听闻你被异地恋困扰着
I hear you're in some sort of a long distance situation?
是啊  拉杰的妹妹
Yeah, it's Raj's sister.
情况比较棘手  她远在印度
It's kind of tough.  She's in India.
她父母也不希望她跟白种人交往
Also, her parents aren't happy she's dating someone white.
那真是个有趣的转机  不是吗
Oh, that's a funny turn, isn't it?
在约会之前  你怎么没想过这个问题呢
You never think about it going the other way.
有些事情你强求不来
Well, you can't force things.
你应该想想你们是否真的是在交往
You need to figure out if you're in a relationship
还是你们只是名义上的
or if you're just calling it one.
就好像常言道  你可以把米放到电锅里
It's like they say--a cat can have kittens in the oven
不代表米就会成炊
but that don't make 'em biscuits.
这提醒了我另外一句常言
And that reminds me of another saying.
你可以诱拐鸡跳炸锅
You can lead a chicken to Crisco,
但不代表你能诱拐你妈去炸鸡
but you can't make your mother fry it.
谢尔顿  你再拿鸡的事情烦我
Sheldon, you pester me one more time about chicken,
我就把你按到我膝盖上  当众打你屁股
I will put you over my knee right here in this restaurant.
求你烦她吧  就当为了我
Please pester her. Please, for me.
库珀夫人  你觉得寿司如何
So, Mrs. Cooper, what did you think of the sushi?
很不错
It was good.
唯一美中不足的是
The only thing that would have made it better
它要是熟食就好了
is if it was cooked
要是夹牛肉 就更棒了
and if it was beef.
谢尔顿  你房东何时能把电梯修理一下
Sheldon, when is your landlord going to fix the elevator?
我不清楚
I don't know.
最近我们有在商量
Lately we've been talking about
把电梯改造成导弹发射井
converting it into a missile silo.
你儿子似乎觉得
Your son seems to think
咱们得先对伯班克发动攻击啊
we need to launch a preemptive strike on Burbank.
先下手为强 后下手遭殃嘛
Get them before they get us.
看看是谁大驾光临了
Hey, look who decided to show up.
拉杰  你搞什么
Raj, what are you doing?
我找不到你们  就买了六个新朋友
I couldn't find you guys so I bought six new friends.
可惜的是  有三个已经阵亡了
Three, sadly, are dead.
妈妈  你记得拉杰吗
Mom, you remember Rajesh?
-拉杰  这位是我妈妈  -当然记得  库珀夫人嘛
- Rajesh, my mother. - Of course.Mrs. Cooper.
很高兴再见到你
So nice to see you again.
我也是
Well, it's so nice to see you, too.
印第安人和印度人都叫Indian
我以为印第安人才偶有酗酒问题
I thought it was our Indians
没想到印度人也会呀
that had the occasional alcohol problem.
这也带歧视  不能说
We don't say that, either.
我回头列个单子给你
I'll make you a list.
你真是太好了  不愧是白人
Oh, that would be mighty white of you.
拉杰  你借酒浇愁
So, Raj, what pain are you trying
是为了什么事
to cover up with alcohol?
没什么  我很好
Nothing, I'm fine.
-是吗  -不  我不好
- Are ya? - No.
这样好多了
That's better.
说说你有什么困扰
Now tell me what's bothering you.
我好孤独
I'm so lonely.
当然了  孤单的出生 孤独的死去
Oh, yes, born alone, die alone.
人类就是如此悲剧
It's a tragic human condition.
拉杰
Now, Raj,
你快别烦我妈了
if you'll excuse my mother,
她要去给我做核桃派
she's about to make a pecan pie
要是好吃
that'll be so good
我就暂时不计较炸鸡的事
I'll almost forget how she blew it with the fried chicken.
谢尔顿  你朋友很伤心
Sheldon, your friend is hurtin'.
这个时候我们该怎么做
What do we do when someone's hurtin'?
给他们倒一杯热饮
Offer them a hot beverage.
而要是他们喝得跟个鬼似的
And when they're drunk as a skunk,
我们该给他们什么饮料
what beverage do we offer?
咖啡
Coffee.
还得要怎样
And what do we do it with?
现在你给我听好
Now you listen to me.
我知道你感觉自己注定是剩男
I know you feel like you can't find someone,
但每个问题都有解决方法
but there's a lock for every key.
以前有个在沃尔玛工作的女孩
Back home, there's a girl works at the Wal-Mart.
长得实在太高
Tall, tall girl.
她用钉耙就能把鹅从空中打下来了
Woman could hunt geese with a rake.
她觉得自己找不到男人
Thought she'd never find a man,
但有一天  谁知道呢
then one day, wouldn't ya know,
Harlem Globetrotters 哈林环球旅行者篮球队
哈林篮球队的人来到镇上
Harlem Globetrotters come to town.
长话短说
Long story short,
现在这个女人和一个
today that woman travels the world
半职业篮球选手周游世界
with a semi-professional basketball player
还生了两个漂亮的混血宝宝
and two beautiful mixed-race babies.
虽然因为你的口音问题我没怎么听懂
I didn't get a lot of that because of your accent,
但你的语气很抚慰人心
but the general tone was soothing
我感觉好多了
and somehow I feel better.
我吃不到核桃派了是吧
I'm not going to get my pecan pie, am I?
你想来点奥利奥吗
You want some Oreos?
-混合夹心的吗  -不是  普通的
- Double Stuf? - No, regular.
不错  真会在伤口上撒盐
Nice. Kick a man when he's down.
很高兴我们终于可以一起做点事情
I'm glad we're finally getting to do something together,
-就我们两个人  -当然
- just the two of us.  - Sure.
出来度假还有衣服要洗  真是开心啊
One thing you really miss when you're on vacation is laundry.
注意点  你松软剂放太多了
Careful, you're using too much Downey.
要是我衣服太柔软  我穿着会想睡觉的
You know if my clothes get too soft it makes me sleepy.
这让我想起了以前的日子
Well, this takes me back.
我帮你洗衣服  而你在旁边碎碎念
Me doing your laundry, you next to me criticizing.
很有爱吧
It is nice, isn't it?
库珀夫人
Mrs. Cooper.
你好  亲爱的
Oh, hello, darlin'.
谢尔顿  你都没告诉我你妈妈要来
Sheldon, you didn't tell me your mom was coming.
我在一周邮件集锦中写了的
It was in my weekly e-mail blast.
就在"甜菜季终于来了"
Right between "Beet season is finally here"
和"神马  甜菜根会致癌"这两条中间
and "Uh-oh, red stool from beets leads to cancer scare."
你最近怎么样
So, how've you been?
很好啊
Good, good.
我听说莱纳德交了新女友
I hear that Leonard has a new girlfriend.
你感觉怎么样
How are you doing with all that?
还好啦  已经过了一阵了
Oh, fine. You know, it's been a while.
我已经重新开始物色对象了
I'm getting back out there.
我多嘴问一句  你物色对象的时候
Let me ask you, when you get back out there,
不会是穿着这个吧
are you wearing this?
这个吊带超好看的
Well, it's super cute on.
全靠它别人才免费请我喝酒
That top has paid for itself in free drinks
省下的酒钱都够买十件了
like ten times what it cost.
对  佩妮的钱基本都是靠滥交来的
Yes, Penny has a lot of her money tied up in promiscuity futures.
亲爱的  你也许该知道
Hon, you think maybe the reason
你一直找不到一个合适的人
why you're having trouble finding a guy to settle down with
是因为你总让男人们先"上"车
is because you're letting them ride the roller coaster
而不让他们掏一个子儿
without buying a ticket?
不是谁都有福分能"上"云霄飞车
Oh, they don't always get to ride the roller coaster.
没福分的就只能在一旁  玩玩咖啡"杯"
Sometimes they only get to spin the teacups.
我今晚要出去
Now I'm going out tonight.
要是我请你帮我选衣服
Would it be crazy to ask you
这样会不会太疯狂了
to look at the outfit I'm going to wear?
一点也不蠢
Oh, not crazy at all.
别看轻自己
And don't beat yourself up.
我像你这么大的时候
When I was your age, you could have me for a car ride
一瓶草莓酒就能骗我出去兜风了
and a bottle of strawberry wine.
我可不会把这个写进本周邮件集锦里
That will not be in this week's e-mail blast.
今年春天
So, this spring,
我要出发去国际空间站
I get to go to the International Space Station.
上帝啊  上天堂呀
Oh, my word, a trip to the heavens.
如果你想在那里定居
If you ever want to live there eternally,
我这有本好书你可以看看
I've got a good book you could read.
心领了  不过我每年都看《查理・布朗的圣诞节》特辑
Thanks, but I watch the Charlie Brown Christmas special every year,
查理・布朗:史努比的主人
所以也不会无聊
so I get the gist.
-你妈妈肯定很以你为荣  -不
- I bet your mom is really proud of you. - Nope.
她说如果我不退出
She says if I don't back out
她就要绝食抗议
she's going to go on a hunger strike.
虽然离出现生命危险
It would take years before
得有好几年时间  但我还是于心不忍
she'd be in any kind of danger, but still.
我们明天去好好玩一天  妈妈
I've got a treat for us tomorrow, Mom.
我要带你
I'm taking you
Saul Perlmutter 2011诺贝尔物理学家得主
去看索尔・珀尔马特演讲
to see Saul Perlmutter give a lecture
他那赢得诺贝尔奖的宇宙学研究成果
about his Nobel Prize-winning work in cosmology.
但最精彩的部分是
And the best part is,
在后面的问答阶段
at the Q and A afterward,
我准备了几个问题
I've worked up a couple of "Q's"
绝对能把他问哭
that will stump his sorry "A."
我不确定  谢利
I don't know, Shelly.
我觉得我们可以去观观光
I thought we could do a little sightseeing.
有什么景色能与你儿子
What sight is better than your little boy
让诺贝尔奖得主颜面扫地相媲美呢
embarrassing a Nobel laureate?
别这样  谢尔顿  我们可以带你妈
Come on, Sheldon, we'll take your mom
去看看好莱坞标志
to see the Hollywood sign,
参观蜡像馆  走走星光大道
the wax museum, the Walk of Fame.
也可以去逛逛罗迪欧大道[名牌商业街]
Ooh, maybe a little Rodeo Drive.
一万二的手袋  我可买不起
Well, I can't spend $12,000 on a handbag,
但用正义的眼光谴责那些
but it's free to look upon those
买得起的人  这倒是不用花钱的
who do with righteous condemnation.
你觉得怎么样
What do you say?
我觉得怎么样
What do I say?
我真心觉得我妈来探望我  关你们屁事
I say you people need to stop ruining my mom's visit
去你的寿司  滚你的悲伤
with your sushi, and your sadness
还有你的放荡小吊带
and your slutty shirts.
你们收手吧
Stop it.
他不是说你  你的衣服密不透风
He's not talking about your shirt. Your shirt is fine.
这真是美味啊
These are delicious.
煎薄饼的秘诀就是用培根油
The trick to pancakes is bacon grease.
我做什么都放这油
I cook everything in it.
每样都放吗  你不怕有害健康吗
Everything? Aren't you worried about your health?
医生说话一向自相矛盾的
Oh, doctors are always changing their mind.
这个星期说你不能吃培根油
One week bacon grease is bad for you.
下个星期就说你吃得不够多
The next week we're not getting enough of it.
早上好  谢利
Good morning, Shelly.
妈妈  我要为我昨晚的行为道歉
Mom, I want to apologize for my behavior last night.
-接受你的道歉  -太好了
- Apology accepted.  - Great.
你会喜欢珀尔马特的演讲的
Now, you're going to love the Perlmutter lecture.
他会说宇宙现在已有六千多年历史
Look, he will be stating that the universe is older than 6,000 years,
我觉得这时你可以用手指塞住耳朵
but I thought you could stick your fingers in your ears
然后低声哼唱《奇异恩典》[基督教圣诗]
and hum "Amazing Grace" during those parts.
我还是要跟你朋友出去
I am still going out with your friends.
可我已经道歉了
But I apologized.
我容易吗我  我又没做错什么
And that was hard for me because I didn't do anything wrong.
谢利  从小到大  那些枯燥无味的演讲
Shelly, I hung out with you in enough dusty lecture halls
我已经陪你听得够多了
while you were growing up.
我现在要去观光
I want to go sightseeing.
你何不吃点煎薄饼
So why don't you have some pancakes,
穿好衣服  跟我们一起去
get dressed and come with us.
我不去  你不能逼我
I'm not going, and you can't make me.
你说得对  我不能逼你  你自个儿玩得开心点
You're right, I can't. Have a nice day.
那我就一直站在这里  直到你回心转意
Well, I'm going to stand here until you change your mind.
那你就在那儿站一天吧
Well, then you are going to stand there all day.
我还是带上我的培根油闪一边去吧
I'm just gonna take my bacon grease and slide over there.
真没想到  我妈妈居然要抛弃我
I can't believe my own mother is abandoning me.
我没有要抛弃你
I am not abandoning you.
谢尔顿  要抛弃你  我早把你放篮子里
Sheldon, abandoning you is leaving you in a basket
扔教堂门口了
on a church doorstep.
我要去好莱坞  对着里根总统的蜡像说
I am going to Hollywood and thank a wax Ronald Reagan
感谢他对国家做的贡献
for his service to our country.
看来我们的母子关系处在十字路口了  妈妈
We appear to be at a crossroads in our relationship, Mother.
看来如此
Well, I guess we are.
不好意思  忘了拿糖浆
Sorry. Syrup.
好吧  妈妈
All right, Mom.
等你进到"瑞普利信不信由你"博物馆
When you're at the Ripley's Believe It Or Not Museum,
在美国田纳西州  纪念Robert Ripley
如果那里有展出情愿扔掉大好机会
if they have an exhibit about a mother who threw away a chance
也不愿陪她的天才儿子玩一天的母亲
to spend the day with the world's most wonderful son,
你要相信  因为真有这种妈妈
believe it, because it's true.
我还没...
I hadn't...
听这场演讲真是浪费时间
That lecture was a waste of time.
我还穿尿布的时候
I made more accurate diagrams
用尿布里的物体  在幼儿园墙上画的
of the expansion of the early universe on the nursery wall
早期宇宙膨胀图都比他的准
with the contents of my diaper.
你是不是病了
Are you getting sick?
不是  只是对那些
No, I'm just allergic to people
平白无故就得诺贝尔奖的人过敏
who get Nobel Prizes for no good reason.
谢尔顿  你心情不好
Sheldon, is it possible that your foul mood--
或者用临床术语说  嘴贱
or, to use the clinical term, bitchiness--
是因为你妈妈没有把你放在第一位
is because your mother isn't making you a priority?
不是  或者用临床术语说  我呸
No. Or to use the clinical term, "nuh-uh""
你确定吗  母婴配对关系
Are you sure? The infant-mother pair-bond
是灵长类动物心理的基础
is the building block of primate psychology.
又来了
Oh, there it is.
什么东西到你嘴里都绕回猴子身上
It always comes back to monkeys with you.
除了猴子  还是猴子
Just monkeys, monkeys, monkeys.
谢尔顿  人类也是动物
Sheldon, we're all animals.
虽然你有一些过人之处
And granted, there are aspects of you that are extraordinary,
但说到情绪和人际关系
but when it comes to emotions and relationships,
你跟普通人没什么两样
you're just like everybody else.
你是说我的情绪问题
Are you trying to suggest that my emotional problems
跟那些白痴没什么两样吗
are no different than those of a stupid person?
实际上  有些研究表明
Actually, some research indicates
不过分考虑的话
that by not overthinking,
智商较低的人  情绪控制得更好
the less intelligent handle emotions better.
你确定你不是感冒了吗
Sure you're not coming down with a cold?
是啊是啊  就跟其他人一样
Oh, yes, the common cold.
得那种普通的感冒呀
Just like everyone else.
那样你就爽了  对吧
You'd love that, wouldn't you?
这间挺漂亮的嘛
Oh, this one's sweet.
对你们这种拿着念珠念经的人来说不错了
You know, for your rosary rattlers.
指天主教念玫瑰经时用一串念珠
库珀太太  那些是天主教徒  不是"拿着念珠念经的人"
Mrs. Cooper, we say "Catholics" not "rosary rattlers".
上帝啊  加利福尼亚怎么这么多条条框框
My goodness, it's a wonder you people in California
还让不让人讲话了
can talk at all.
这真是史上最烂的好莱坞之旅了
This is like the worst Hollywood tour ever.
咱有什么办法  谁叫她非要逛教堂呢
What are we gonna do? She wanted to see churches.
教堂里有酒的  对吧
Hey, they have wine here, don't they?
我们印度的神可没有这么强壮的腹肌
None of our gods have abs like that.
没错  这是最后一个坚持做仰卧起坐的犹太人
Yep, that's the last Jew who did sit-ups.
可你看看他的下场
And look where it got him.
既然咱们都来了  何不一块祷告呢
Hey, while we're here, why don't we all do some praying?
给这个教堂也添点教堂的气氛嘛
Let's put a little church in this church.
我觉得我们不...
Oh, I'm not sure we should...
很简单的  我教你
It's easy. I'll show you how.
主啊  玛丽・库珀在此
Lord, Mary Cooper here.
我从加利福尼亚州的蛾摩拉城前来膜拜
Coming to you from Gomorrah, California.
蛾摩拉城是圣经中的罪恶之都
我想感谢您
I want to thank you
保佑我的小宝贝谢利
for the blessing that is my little Shelly.
我还想感谢您一直赐予我宽容的力量
I also want to thank you for the continued strength
我才没用圣经把他给拍晕
not to coldcock him with my Bible.
好了  佩妮  到你了
All right, Penny, your turn.
好吧
Okay, um...
好呀  上帝
Hey, God.
最近咋样啊
What's up?
我挺好的  但是
Um, I'm good, but, uh,
您要是能阻止我哥造冰毒的话
it would be a big help to my family
那就是帮了我们家大忙了
if you could get my brother to stop cooking meth.
但是别惊动警察  私下解决就好
But no cops. Be cool.
她还有点太爱她的邻居了
She also goes a little overboard
都爱上床了
on the "love thy neighbor" .
或许可以像解救抹大拉的玛丽亚那样帮帮她
Could probably use that chat you had with Mary Magdalene.
被耶稣解救的妓女
莱纳德  到你了
Leonard, you're up.
那个叫沃什么的  你做好准备
Wasserman, you're on deck.
好吧  说啥呢
Okay. I don't know...
现在再求你让我长高点  可能有点太晚了
it's probably a little late to ask you to make me taller.
对了  也许你可以帮帮我和我的女朋友
Oh, um...if you could help out with me and my girlfriend.
她现在远在印度  你要是能帮我们一下就好了
She's all the way in India. That would be great.
听见没  恋情烦恼
Hear that? Girl trouble.
看来我们都没想到莱纳德也能交上女朋友
Turns out we were both wrong on that front.
-你呢  -我
- How about you?  - Oh, me?
不用了  我没啥愿望
No. Thanks, I'm good.
我只盼着宇宙飞船别突然爆炸就行
I'm really just trying not to burst into flames.
拉杰呢
Rajesh?
他说他那最后的五磅体重
He says he's having trouble
怎么都减不下去
dropping those last five pounds.
要是我就求主解决  我不敢跟女孩子讲话的问题
Huh, I might have gone with the talking-to-girls thing.
不行  你一次只能许一个愿
No, you only get one wish.
美国著名演员  Martin Sheen
看看咱俩
Look at the two of us.
我  一位受人尊敬的物理学家
Me, a highly regarded physicist.
一两代人里才偶然出现一个的
The kind of mind that comes along once,
超级高智商
maybe twice in a generation.
你呢  就是个普通人
You, the common man,
股票经纪  要不就是吸尘机销售员
tired from your labors as a stockbroker,
再不然就是个擦皮鞋的  累得半死刚下班
or vacuum cleaner salesman, or bootblack.
但是内心深处
But deep down inside...
咱俩也就是一丘之貉
apparently we're just two peas in a pod.
只不过你是个普通的貉
A regular pea,
而我是个一两代才出那么一个的
and the kind of pea that comes along once,
高等貉
maybe twice in a generation.
下雨了
Rain.
又一个象征着众人平等的标志
Another great equalizer.
雨浇在我这个天才头上
Falling on the head of the brilliant
也浇在你这个凡人头上
and the unremarkable alike.
真有先见之明
Smarty-pants.
库珀太太  你做的饭太香了
Oh, Mrs. Cooper, it smells so good.
记着我的话  亲爱的
You take notes, darlin'.
拴住一个男人真正的秘诀就是给他做
The real way to get a man is with melted cheese
融化的奶酪和奶油蘑菇汤
and cream of mushroom soup.
虽然他五十岁就挂掉  但在那之前绝对会全心爱你
He'll die at 50 but his love will be true.
给我张纸巾  这张湿了
I need a tissue. This one got wet.
给你
Here.
谢谢  我今天学到东西了
Thank you. Yeah, I've learned something today.
你和我  在很多方面
You and I, in so many ways,
除了智商和其他重要方面
other than intelligence and what counts,
其实没什么不同
we're the same
-亲爱的  你生病了吗  -但愿如此
- Sweetheart, are you sick? - I hope so.
如果这都不叫生病  那活着还有什么意义
because if this is well, life isn't worth living.
宝贝儿  你发烧了
Oh, sugarpie, you are burning up.
-赶快上床躺着去吧  -好吧
- We've got to get you to bed.  - Okay.
别担心  妈妈来照顾小宝贝儿
Don't worry. Mama's here to take care of her baby.
咱先说清楚  你只照顾自己的宝贝儿
And just to be clear, only her baby
而不是所有这些宝贝儿对吧
and not these other people.
那当然
Of course.
我想喝蜂蜜茶
Can I have tea with honey
吃去边的三明治  可以吗
and toast with the crust cut off?
你想吃什么都行
You can have whatever you want.
谢谢妈妈  你最好了
Thanks, Mom. You're the best.
天啊  上次我帮你涂药膏的时候
Boy, last time I put VapoRub on you,
你还没长出胸毛来呢
you didn't have hair on your chest.
是啊  去年才长出来的
I know, it filled in last year.
你这次来  我都没跟你在一起待多久
I didn't get to spend a lot of time with you on this visit.
这是谁的错啊
And whose fault was that?
你的错
Yours.
谢利  你已经不再是个八岁的小孩子了
Shelly, you're not eight years old anymore.
咱俩之间的关系不能跟以前一样了
We have to have a different relationship.
不要
No, we don't.
咱俩之前那样就挺好的呀
The one we have works great.
亲爱的  你是个大人了
Sweetheart, you are a grown man.
没准我是个
Or maybe I'm part of a new species,
寿命长达上百年的新物种呢
that lives for hundreds of years,
也就是说我现在还是个两三岁的孩子呢
which means I'm still basically a toddler.
我当年真应该带你去休斯顿
Oh, I so should have taken you to Houston.
也就是说你不会唱《乖乖猫》给我听了吗
Does this mean you're not going to sing "Soft Kitty"?
不  我永远都会唱《乖乖猫》给你听的
No, I will always sing you "Soft Kitty".
乖乖猫  暖暖猫
Soft kitty，warm kitty
小小毛绒球
Little ball of fur...
库珀太太  我们是不是该把那个派
Mrs. Cooper, were we supposed to take that pie
-从烤箱里拿出来了  -滚
- out of the oven? - Get out!
这也太没礼貌了
Well, that was rude.
就是啊  不过他也不是故意的
Well, I know, but he means well.
继续唱吧
Sing.
快乐猫  瞌睡猫
Happy kitty,sleepy kitty
你是想偷懒吗  妈
What are you trying to pull, Mom?
从头开始唱
From the top.
我就说他欠揍嘛
This is what I'm talking about.
乖乖猫  暖暖猫
Soft kitty，warm kitty
小小毛绒球
Little ball of fur...